Subtitles by explosiveskull
♪ Welcome to Cargo, my hometown ♪
♪ Full of friendly autos ♪
♪ Red and green and brown ♪
♪ The residents are pretty swell ♪
♪ And I can tell, I know them well ♪
♪ The children here are well-behaved ♪
♪ But I wish the streets
were better paved ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, it's a heck of a town ♪
♪ With some streets going up ♪
♪ And others going down ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, to
us, it's very clear ♪
♪ If this is where you lived ♪
♪ You'd be home by now ♪
♪ So move your family here ♪
♪ The folks live in garage houses ♪
♪ On lovely tree-lined streets ♪
♪ We always smile and beep hello ♪
♪ To every car we meet ♪
♪ Of course, the
occasional traffic jam ♪
♪ Makes you feel a
little crammed, but ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, it's a heck of a town ♪
♪ With some streets going up ♪
♪ And others going down ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, to
us, it's very clear ♪
♪ If this is where you lived ♪
♪ You'd be home by now ♪
♪ So move your family here ♪
Class, come to order.
You'd all better pay attention
if you want to pass the
surprise quiz this afternoon.
Surprise quiz? I didn't study.
Oh, Danny Carbunkle, super
A student, didn't study.
A car after my own heart.
It's your fault, Vin.
If you hadn't convinced me to
go racing, I would have studied.
Don't blame me, brain boy.
You're a natural racer.
Do you two boys want to share your secrets
with the rest of the class?
No, Ms. Edsel. We were just saying
how lucky we are to
have a teacher like you.
Is that true, Danny?
Um, uh...
Just what I thought.
You two are staying after school
to write 100 times, "I
will not beep in class."
Well, thank you, Ms. Edsel.
It is a very appropriate punishment.
Do you really think you're
fooling me, Vincent Diesel?
Mr. Oil Wouldn't Melt in my Crankcase?
Okay, class, recess.
See you in 30 minutes.
Oh, and be prepared to
pass the surprise test.
I wonder why she keeps
calling it a surprise test?
It'll be a surprise, all right,
when I fail it.
You, fail it?
You're only the best student in school.
Cabigail, I went racing with Vin
yesterday instead of studying.
I've told you a million times.
That jalopy is a bad influence on you.
He's all right.
No, he isn't.
He's a juvenile delinquent.
If I fail this test,
my dad will have to put me up on blocks.
Look, you can always pretend to be sick
to get out of taking the test.
Brilliant idea. Tell me, Vin,
when you're in juvenile detention garage,
would you rather work in the
laundry or make license plates?
I am never going to juvie
again. I am way too smart.
Danny, bud, the old pukey
routine is your best bet.
Now, of course, I don't expect you
to perform with the skill of yours truly.
It really is an art.
Danny, don't do it.
You're better than that.
Yeah, don't do it. No, no.
No, don't do that.
You're more chicken than that.
Okay, class, the quiz will begin
with this math problem, and...
Danny, what's wrong?
I don't feel so good.
Eww.
You'd better go to the nurse.
Sure. I'll take him, Ms. Edsel, me.
Thank you, Vincent.
And hurry back!
Sure will. Won't miss
this test for the world.
Wait a minute.
This isn't the way to the nurse's office.
Cool it, Danny boy. We are going AWOL.
I shouldn't.
I can't believe you are such a coward.
Be bold, bro. That's where the fun is.
But I...
It's time you take some risks and be bold.
Where are we going?
To the races, my man!
Let's see what you got!
I'll get suspended!
Not to mention, my dad
will cut off my ignition.
Only if you get caught.
♪ Go where the fun is ♪
♪ And don't sit around and mope ♪
♪ If all you do is study ♪
♪ Then you're just a big old dope ♪
♪ There's lots of fun to have ♪
♪ If you just break some rules ♪
♪ You won't amount to anything ♪
♪ By studying for school ♪
♪ Don't be a loner
buried in some books ♪
♪ Just go where the fun is ♪
♪ Then you won't be a schnook ♪
♪ If everyone is doing it ♪
♪ Then it can't be so bad ♪
♪ The only one who disagrees ♪
♪ Is your strict old dad ♪
This is an illegal race, Vin!
I don't want to end up in juvie!
Juvie ain't so bad.
Three cans of oil a day
and a garage of your own to idle in.
Yeah, with bars on the windows.
Oh, come on, man.
What are you worried about?
If you win this race, you'll be a star
in the world of underground, illegal,
very dangerous street racing.
Okay, I'll do it.
Peer pressure, ain't it great?
On your mark! Get set!
- Go!
- Whoo-hoo!
Come on!
Whoop. Whoop. Whoop. Whoop.
Pull over!
I said pull over!
Vin, what did you get me into?
Dude, it's every car for itself. See ya!
Oh, no! Nuts! Nuts!
My dad is gonna kill me!
Pull over!
I said pull over!
Oh!
Ah! Ha!
Hmm.
Danny? What are you doing home?
Uh, I didn't feel well,
so I came home.
Hmph. Go up to your room.
I'll be in to check under
your hood in a minute.
Sick, huh?
Heh. I don't think so.
What's come over Danny?
♪ What do you do when
you've got a kid ♪
♪ That's the result of
everything you did? ♪
♪ What do you do when
your kid's a car ♪
♪ That's a chip off the engine block ♪
♪ Of everything you are ♪
♪ You got to teach him
to slow down on curves ♪
♪ To stick to the
straightaways and not swerve ♪
♪ To avoid the potholes ♪
♪ On the streets of life ♪
♪ And one day be the man car ♪
♪ That can get a wife ♪
♪ You've got to show
him not to go too fast ♪
♪ To change his tires
and make them last ♪
♪ To beep his horn, but not too loud ♪
♪ To do everything to make me proud ♪
♪ Teach him to work ♪
♪ Teach him the skills ♪
♪ Don't be a jerk, always pay bills ♪
♪ You can shape his life ♪
The boy needs a Dad, not a friend.
♪ Do what you did, be a mechanic ♪
♪ Save him from Clunker Island ♪
♪ I'm just a teenaged car ♪
♪ And no one understands me ♪
♪ A teenaged car ♪
♪ Dad always reprimands me ♪
♪ If I could do my thing ♪
♪ It'll all turn out okay ♪
♪ But to him, I'm just a kid ♪
♪ I have nothing to say ♪
♪ Just a teenaged car ♪
♪ And no one understands me ♪
♪ A teenaged car ♪
♪ They only reprimand me ♪
♪ One day, I'll be a grownup car ♪
♪ And then I'll have a ball ♪
♪ Driving with high octane ♪
♪ Then I'll show ♪
♪ And then I'll show them all ♪
Okay, open your mouth, and say, "Ahh."
Do I have to?
Open your mouth,
and say "Ahhhhhh."
Ahh.
Oil seems normal.
Maybe you should go back to school.
No, Dad. I still feel all pukey and stuff.
Okay, then. I'll take your temperature.
Are you sure you're not faking this
because you didn't study for some test?
Who, me?
If you are faking it and I find out,
you'll be put on blocks for a week.
I hated that movie.
It was just too unrealistic.
A tornado full of cars. Could never happen!
They just don't make 'em like they used to.
When I was your age, I was
in love with Greta Carbo,
and I wanted to be Sean Carnerry.
Say, you do have a fever.
Stay under your tarp until dinner.
I'll make your favorite, WD-40 soup.
Not again!
What's that?
Uh, I said, "Oh, boy!
What luck. My favorite!"
Dinner at 6:00 sharp.
I'll study until then.
That's my boy.
Hey, Danny, I was thinking.
Yeah?
Maybe you should come to my garage with me,
start learning the
tricks of the trade again.
I don't know, Dad.
When you were younger, you always loved it.
Who knows? Maybe the shop
will be yours one day.
I don't want to be a mechanic, Dad.
I don't know what I want to be.
It's something you're good at.
It's in your oil.
Think about it.
Vin could be right.
Being bad is a lot more
fun than being good.
Until you get caught.
Hey, Cabigail. What's up?
You're not really sick, are you?
- Technically...
- Actually.
Uh, no, but I almost won a race today.
I was this close!
And then the cop showed up,
so I had to take it on the lam.
So you're making some real
good choices these days.
You really think so?
No. I think you're being an idiot.
You could be the best student in school
and the most popular car in
Cargo if you applied yourself.
But where's the fun,
the thrills, the danger?
That's not you, Danny.
You wouldn't say that. That's Vin talking.
Yeah? Well, maybe Vin has it right.
Don't be brainwashed.
You're smarter than this, Danny.
You care about school
and cars and your family.
Stop pretending to be
cool, and just be you.
I'm not pretending, Cabs!
I'm being bold.
You should try it sometime.
Get your fender out of your tailpipe!
Hello.
Dude, the race is on for tonight.
Are you in or what?
No! No!
Don't do it, Danny!
You are way smarter than this!
Danny, do you know who that car is?
That's Rudy Carleone.
His dad is Don Carleone.
La Carsanostra?
The same.
I don't think you should race against him.
Why not? A race is a race.
That car plays for keeps.
Uh, what does that mean?
I don't think you want to find out.
On your mark!
Get set!
Go!
Not again.
Every single time!
Get closer! I dare you!
I'll make your wheels pop like balloons.
Stay down, Carbunkle,
if you know what's good for you!
Oh, jeez!
Danny...
ever go on a
slip-and-slide?
What?
See you, suckers!
Eat my dust! Hah hah!
Oh!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Dude, that Rudy is a creep.
Let's show him, Danny Boy.
What did you have in mind?
Come on, man. Just follow my lead.
What kept you boys?
I was getting worried.
You should worry.
You should worry a lot!
You know who my father is, right?
Yeah, we know.
Oh, yeah, him?
He's the father of the big, fat loser.
Vin, what are you doing?
Look, if he's playing dirty, so are we.
Hey!
I'm sorry.
Ah!
Please be okay, Danny.
Please be okay.
Pull over!
I said pull over!
Dispatch, we have a 302
street race in progress.
Pulled over two cars, but I have a red car
still speeding down on Leaded Street.
Please send backup.
Copy that, Sir.
You kids are in a lot of trouble!
Your friend that just ran
is probably going away for a long time.
We didn't mean to.
Everyone knows the speed
limit in our town is 35 MPH!
No one ever goes higher than
that unless they are racing.
We're... Look, I'm sorry. I had no idea.
We must have been, what, two, three, five
over the speed limit, if that?
I-I'm sorry.
You were going 90!
Street racing is illegal!
What are you gonna do to us?
Names and pink slips!
Vin Diesel.
Danny Carbunkle.
You Art Carbunkle's kid?
Yes.
I'm gonna let you kids off with a warning.
You're lucky I know your father.
He's got a good engine on his shoulders.
But the next time I catch
you illegally racing,
it's juvenile detention garage for you!
Yes, sir.
I have speed traps all around town.
No race goes on around
here without me finding out.
You better start driving the
straight and narrow, Danny Carbunkle.
I've got my headlights on you.
Dude, see? I told you
that you were good luck!
I thought we were getting
locked up for sure.
What's your problem?!
You almost killed Rudy!
That's not okay, man!
Oh, come on, man.
Quit being such a wet
car blanket, Carbunkle!
He was playing cheap, so
I had to even the odds.
Someone could have gotten hurt!
Isn't that the point?
Vin, I don't know if this
racing thing is for me.
This is too much. I think I'm done.
Once you get a taste of winning,
you're never really done, Danny.
If my dad found out I
was racing, he'd kill me!
What?
He...
What's wrong? Are you choking?
Danny...
He's right behind me, isn't he?
Later, Danny!
Dad!
Daniel Carbunkle...
Listen, Dad. I...
You what, made a stupid decision?
Heh. I knew you were faking being sick.
How?
You don't think I'm hip
to the thermometer in the exhaust?
I was a kid once, too, Danny.
You don't understand me!
I do, Danny. You don't realize
you and I have more in
common than you think.
I was just like you when I was your age.
I got into a lot of trouble,
but I learned my lesson.
I don't want to see
you drive the same path.
I'm not, Dad! Stop being ridiculous!
I just don't want to
see you end up like me.
I won't. I'm not a loser.
What was that?
You heard me!
You need to grow up
and start taking life seriously.
Danny, you aren't a kid anymore.
Why can't I just have
fun being a kid, be bold?
Forget it! You don't remember
what it's like to be a kid,
to have fun, to take risks!
I'll never be a stupid mechanic.
I'll be something cool, like a race car.
I earn an honest living
and provide for this family.
It's time you appreciate hard work.
Hard work, my bumper!
Danny Carbunkle, you are grounded!
I don't know what made you
think you're such a tough car,
but it's time you learn your lesson.
You need to start actually
taking life seriously.
I didn't raise you like this.
Why can't you just be cool for once?
I'm your Dad, Danny, not your friend.
Well, maybe you need to
learn to be my friend.
Maybe we would get along better.
You only have one Dad, Danny.
I would be an awful parent
to take that away from you.
I'm trying to save your life.
Can't you see that?
I just see you ruining my life!
Let's go.
Dad, I'm capable of driving home on my own.
No, you aren't.
I hate you!
I never want to talk to you again!
Sometimes we have to do the
right thing, no matter the cost.
Come on!
Dad, this is so embarrassing!
Maybe you'll think
about that the next time.
Pull over!
You'll never catch me, copper!
I can do it myself!
Danny, stop it!
No!
Danny, stop!
Unhook me!
Look out!
No!
Dad!
Oh, no.
Dad, answer me! Dad.
I'm calling an ambulance.
I feel funny.
Danny, are you all right?
All incoming patients need to
checked in at the front garage.
What happened?
You passed out.
And you betrayed me.
No, I didn't.
You didn't want me to race,
so you called the cops.
Don't be ridiculous.
Fred Copcar has speed
traps all around town.
Yeah, sure.
Danny...
Where's my dad?
They took him to ICU.
What's that?
Intensive Car Unit.
Oh, no!
Danny, wait!
Stop following me.
Haven't you done enough?
I'm just trying to be here for you, Danny.
Well, can you just be over there for me?
Stop being mean!
Did you see that horrible car wreck?
Dumb street racers.
They're talking about my dad!
You don't know that.
I know!
I want to see Art Carbunkle!
What room is he in?
- And who are you to him?
- His son.
T-bone or
rear-end?
I, uh...
T-bone.
Ah, yes. Let me look him up for you.
I'm sorry.
What?
He's been totaled.
- Totaled?
- Yes.
He's on his way to Clunker
Island in the morning.
Clunker Island?
Not Clunker Island!
W-What's Clunker Island?
I thought that was just a made-up place
that parents would
threaten their kids with.
Like, "Take your antifreeze,
or I'll send you to Clunker Island."
Oh, no. It's a real place, all right.
When a car is totaled
and loses its pink slip,
it's relegated to Clunker Island,
where it's used for spare parts
until there's nothing useful left.
Poor kid.
Hate to see that.
Next!
I think I just need an oil change.
I think we've got another
one for Clunker Island.
No, really, just an oil change.
Really! Just an oil change!
Oil change! No!
Not Clunker Island! No! No! Aah!
I have to find Danny!
Dad?
Dad.
I'm sorry, Dad.
It's all my fault.
I thought I'd find you here.
So you found me.
So what?
You gonna call the cops again?
I never called the cops.
I wish you'd believe me.
I wish I could, too.
Danny, it's gonna be all right.
My dad loved this place.
Now I'm never gonna see him again.
That's not true. We just
gotta go to Clunker Island.
You act like it's easy.
Two hours ago, you didn't
even know it was real.
Well, that's half the battle, right?
Let's go to Clunker Island.
I just want to go home.
Let's go to the ferry.
Let's go to Clunker Island.
Oh, sure, we'll just roll
right up to the ferryman
and say, "Two tickets to Clunker Island."
That oughta work!
It's worth a try.
Sorry. Clunker Island is only for clunkers.
Come back in about 40 years.
I told you this wasn't gonna work.
We've got to find some other
way to get to Clunker Island.
Nothing ever works out easy.
I just want to be left alone.
Well, you need to snap out of it.
Why is that?
We need to save your dad. Come on!
I guess there's one way,
but you aren't gonna like it.
I'm listening.
We've gotta become clunkers!
And how are we gonna do that?
By using this!
Your crankcase?
No, my brain.
Well, I didn't know you had one of those.
Well, hah hah. Real funny.
We need to focus here.
So what's the real plan then?
We gotta go to the Demolition Derby.
You can't be serious.
Deadly serious.
That place is deadly serious.
I don't know if this is
such a good idea, Danny.
Trust me! It's gonna be great!
I just need to go in,
get banged up a little bit, and survive.
Then, boom, it's a
ticket to Clunker Island.
"Survive," that's the key word.
This is too dangerous.
That's the point, Cabs.
I need to be bold here.
Will you stop it with that already?
This is suicide.
Only if it doesn't work.
I have an idea.
Why don't we just go there instead?
No way! This will be much better.
But that will be much safer.
Maybe the theater people can
do our makeup to look totaled.
It won't be believable enough.
Danny, please?
Just follow my lead.
Nah, youse kids ain't old
enough for the Demo Derby.
Why don't you go home and
play with your dollies?
We're really a lot older than we look.
Yeah? Let me see your registrations.
Um, we forgot it.
Yeah. Older cars like us forget things.
I ain't buying it! Now beat it,
before I call my carleagues
and have youse escorted off the premiseses!
What are you doing?
Cabbie, do I look different?
Different? No. Why?
'Cause geniuses sometimes look different.
Why are you suddenly a genius?
Because I just had a genius idea.
Look. Let's go shopping for costumes.
You mean let's go stealing.
No way!
You said earlier maybe
they'll do our makeup.
Well, maybe they'll lend
us a costume for an hour.
I don't know, Danny.
Oh, come on! It was
your idea to begin with.
Whatever.
Chromio, Chromio,
wherefore art thou, Chromio?
We kinda did that earlier, didn't we,
when I was at your window?
It was really nice of those actors
to say we could borrow these costumes.
Yeah. Almost seemed too good to be true.
I wonder why they were so cool about it.
Oh, I love this part,
when Chromio says to Tooliette...
Tell me later. We gotta split now.
Great. You the understudies?
My main actors are out of gas. You're on.
Uh, actually,
we were just gonna borrow
some costumes for an hour?
Yeah. The actors told me.
You guys are now their understudies.
You have to go onstage.
- What?
- Go!
Chromio, Chromio,
wherefore art thou, Chromio?
Uh, what?
Just go with it. I know
all the lines to this play.
Fine.
We just saw this part.
Oh.
Uh, a car by any other name
would still smell as sweet as you, Chromio.
Have not cars fenders
and holy bumpers, too?
Aye, pilgrim, fenders that
they must use in prayer.
Oh, then, dear saint, let
fenders do what tires do.
Shakescar, so brilliant.
How 'bout that? Was that cool?
More! More!
You know, I found Shakescar
so boring before that.
You are my moon, my stars, my sky.
I rise when you rise
and fall when you fall,
for my night is dark without you.
You are my life, my love, my true.
I will follow you till the ends
of the Earth to be by your side.
We will save your father.
Whoa. I really gotta see this play.
Lots in common.
No other lady will love you
as much as I, Tooliette, love Dan...
I mean Chromio.
Yay!
Good going in there!
You really saved us, knowing
all those lines from the play.
Oh, thanks.
I didn't know you could act.
Yeah, uh, acting.
Least we have the costumes now.
These costumes are beautiful.
Hey, remember, the idea
is not to look beautiful,
but to look old and beat-up.
Do you think I look beautiful?
Beautiful? Uh, no. I didn't say you were.
I mean, we're friends.
Like, your eyes were, uh,
um, what I, uh...
Yeah, I mean, you are cool, I-I guess.
Wait. So which is it?
Am I cool, or am I beautiful?
Uh, I mean, you are, um...
Your eyes are, like, um...
smart.
My eyes are smart?
Yeah, that's it.
You have smart eyes.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
But we need to dirty up these costumes.
Man, you two look way
too old for the Derby.
What? Speak up, sonny!
Look, kids, I'm not buying it for a second.
Youse guys are just
wearing some costumeses.
No, we're not.
Yes, you are.
I heard your plan, like, an hour ago.
We're old cars.
If youse guys got that
much of a death wish,
you can just come on in,
but don't say I didn't warn youse!
What does he mean by that?
These cars are crazy.
And I must be the craziest of all.
You mean, we must be the craziest of all.
No, Cabbie, I can't let you do this.
It's too dangerous.
- But I thought...
- No.
You wait for me,
and when I get totaled, I'll find some way
to sneak you onto Clunker Island.
Danny, no!
Well, well, well,
we've got a new contestant
in the Demolition Derby.
Let's hear it for, uh,
uh, Chromio Shakescar,
an old, old car with a young carburetor.
Watch out, Chromio.
That truck means business.
Yowza! That was close!
Ohh! He came out of nowheres!
Mama, I'm coming.
Oh, Mama, are those your blinkers?
I see your lights, Mama.
I'm coming.
Watch out, man.
Look at that old car go!
I want to tell you, it's mayhem, mayhem!
You the car, Danny!
I mean, Chromio! Whoo-hoo!
Uh-oh, it's the Demo Derby champion,
the Colossus of Crunch,
the Annihilator of Annihilation,
the wrecker of cars,
the one, the only Monster Truck!
And this dude is bad
with a capital B-A-D!
You're going to Clunker
Island, loser, in pieces!
You'll have to catch me first.
Well, you don't have to be rude.
Sorry. I...
Shut up! I was just kidding!
Say your prayers, poser!
Move our of the way!
Where'd you go, you little creep?
I thought you deserved a good spanking.
Oh! Whoa!
You'll pay for that!
You'll be leaking oil when
I get my wheels on you!
Uh-oh! I'm stalling!
Oh, no! Danny, get out of there!
Do you believe in miracles?
We have a new champion!
Let's hear for him, folks,
Chromio Shakescar!
This isn't over. I'll be back for you.
Sure, you will.
You did it!
I know! I can't believe I won!
You seriously showed that
Monster Truck who's boss!
Thanks, Cabs!
I guess I'm the Demolition champion!
Amazing!
I couldn't have done it
without you cheering me on.
Oh, stop.
Anyways, let's go to Clunker Island.
Oh, man.
What?
I wasn't supposed to
win the Demolition Derby.
I was supposed to get totaled in it.
Oh, yeah. I guess I just got
so caught up in the moment.
Chromio Shakescar,
or should I say Danny Carbunkle?
That's my name. What's up?
Danny, that's...
When you're addressing the Don,
you will refer to him as Don Carleone.
Yes, of course.
Uh, thank you, Mr. Don Carleone.
It's very serendipitous
that you should meet me
here today on the day of son's totaling.
What's "serendipitous" mean?
It means coincidence, you numskull.
Rudy!
Rudy? You're alive.
Yeah, I'm alive, no thanks to you.
I tried to help you, man
You totaled my dad!
Your dad totaled me!
Now I can't race.
That sounds like a you problem.
He insulted the Don's son!
You want us to drain him, boss?
Nah, he'll be on empty.
No more gas.
No. Let the boy speak.
Because it was Vin that bumped
me during the race and not you,
I'm willing to let bygones be bygones
if you race for me, a pink-slip challenge.
If you lose, your pink slip is gone,
and you're considered totaled,
so you either win me someone's
pink slip or forfeit yours.
If you lose, though, it's
off to Clunker Island.
What? So if I lose,
I get sent to Clunker Island?
Ain't you ever heard of La Carsanostra?
So, you better say yes,
'cause we never, ever, never, ever,
ever, never, ever, ever
ever hear the word "no."
I don't even know what that means!
No, no, no, really.
What does that word mean?
I'm asking for a friend.
Both of you, shut up.
You're giving me a carburetor-ache.
This is perfect! All I have to do is lose!
I can do that.
Are you sure?
Your instinct is to win.
But if I lose, I win.
So, Danny, are you racing for us or what?
Yep.
You made me an offer I couldn't refuse.
An offer you couldn't refuse.
I like that.
Has a nice ring to it.
Can I use it?
It's all yours.
The name's Speedy Fireball,
and that's just what I am.
I'm speedy, and I'm a fireball,
hence the name, Speedy Fireball.
I get it. You're Speedy Fireball.
Heard of me, eh? No wonder.
I am the best.
I am speedy, and...
I get it! You're a fireball
with a pretty high opinion of yourself.
Perhaps that's because I never
lost a race to a punk like you.
Okay, now I'm mad.
I'll show that stuck-up jerk!
But, Danny...
Let's get this race started!
Okay, this is for the pink slips.
Danny Carbunkle, stepping in for my son,
versus Speedy Fireball.
I hope you remember why you're doing this.
Losers say what?
- What?
- Exactly.
Okay, guys, I want a clean race, all right?
Keep your engines clean!
Ready?
Set!
Go!
Pull over!
Damn speed traps.
Not again!
I said pull over!
Did I win?
You would have, but
then you would have lost.
What?
Oh, yeah, that's right!
Why do I keep doing this?
I seriously mess everything up.
I don't know what comes over me.
- Uh-oh.
- What?
It's Officer Fred Copcar.
Hey, Officer.
Nice night for a stroll, isn't it?
Don't play dumb!
You were racing again, Danny.
I really didn't mean to this time.
I was forced to.
I warned you kids.
Pink slips.
What?
Hand 'em over!
I'm gonna write you up.
I, um, don't have mine.
That Don Carleone was holding it.
Mine, too, and then they just took off.
Why did he have yours?
I was gonna race if you lost.
I mean, won.
I don't know about that "Don Carleone"
and that other car you were racing,
but I know you,
and I'm afraid you really did it this time.
Please, please, you don't understand!
I need to save my dad.
He's on Clunker Island.
It's juvenile detention garage for you.
What?!
Me, too!
You want to go to juvie?
I want to go wherever Danny goes.
You do?
♪ I want to go where you go ♪
♪ I want to begin where you end ♪
♪ I want to share in whatever comes ♪
♪ 'Cause I want to be your friend ♪
♪ Ever since I was a little car ♪
♪ I thought ♪
♪ You were good and
tender, strong, and true ♪
♪ I thought ♪
♪ I wanted to be everywhere you are ♪
♪ To be stuck to your front fender ♪
♪ We're car buddies
through tragedy or fun ♪
♪ Though we are two
very different cars ♪
♪ Our engines hum as one ♪
♪ I want to go where you go ♪
♪ I want to run where you run ♪
♪ I want to begin where you end ♪
♪ 'Cause I want to be your friend ♪
♪ I want to be everywhere you are ♪
♪ Oh, everywhere under the sun ♪
Cabigail, don't be silly.
Don't you care that I care?
Sure, I care that you care,
but I don't care to see you incarcerated.
That's so sweet.
Wait a minute! I'm not saying
that I care the way that you care.
It's just that...
Young love, very touching.
Who, us?
We're not in love.
We're just friends.
Yeah, friends.
Like, "Oh, man,
I love her like my friend."
And I love you, like my friend.
Well, you guys have plenty
of time to figure that out,
'cause you're both going to the slammer!
Take 'em away, boys.
Yes, sir.
Oh, no.
You guys better put on cruise control,
'cause you got a long ride ahead of you.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Attention all inmates.
Today's lunch will be engine
oil. Served at twelve o'clock.
Don't forget if you're in the yard,
you have to wear your orange paint.
This is all your fault!
Oh, my fault? How is this my fault?
You said we could save my dad.
You were the one that put that crazy idea
in my head in the first place.
Crazy idea?
Danny, I've been here
helping you the whole time!
Well, a lot of good that's done us.
Now we're stuck here.
We'll figure out a way.
You always think of something.
Oh, dude, Carbunkle! What's up?
Vin! You left me, dude!
What the heck?
Dude, I thought you were totaled, man.
You went to the hospital.
You ditched me!
No, I didn't. Trust me.
You should have seen you.
I thought you were gone for sure.
How'd you get here?
Our friendly local cop,
Officer Fred Copcar, of course.
I think he has a crush on me, dude.
He's always following me around and stuff.
Cool.
I mean, uh, that's too bad.
It's okay.
Hey, you want to bust out
of this joint, Danny Boy?
I got a plan so crazy,
no one will ever know.
I'd love to break out, but me and Cabigail
have to get to Clunker Island.
Clinker Island?
Why would you want to go to Clinker Island?
Clunker Island, you idiot!
Yeah, whatever.
I don't need to speak words like you guys.
I just need to know how to use them.
That makes absolutely no sense.
Danny, how are you friends with this guy?
I have a plan. Youse in or out?
I've gotta get to Clunker
Island to save my dad.
He was totaled.
I never knew my dad.
I wish I had a dad.
Don't cry.
You're getting your windshield all smudged.
Crying? Who... No. Who's crying?
It's just... just the
windshield wiper fluid leak.
Tough guys don't cry.
Anyway, Clinker Island is right next-door.
It is?
It's Clunker!
What did I tell you
about correcting me with words?
It's actually super-duper
easy to get there.
Really?
Sure, the easiest.
All you gotta do is
tunnel under the wall here,
find your way through
the Impossible Forest,
drive across Dangerous Bridge,
and take the ferry at
Port Incredibly Risky.
Easy-peasy.
That sounds extremely
difficult and dangerous.
No. Trust me. It's easy.
How do you know that?
Come on, man.
'Cause it's three things.
All easy things always come in threes.
Everyone knows that.
I don't think we can trust him.
He sounds like an idiot,
and he just left you before.
I don't think we have a choice.
How have you ever listened
to anything he said?
He makes absolutely no sense.
So you in, Danny?
You want to bust out of here, or what?
I'm institutionalized.
Ain't gonna make it on the outside.
What's he talking about?
- No clue.
- Oh, come on!
Neither of you have seen
"The Carshank Redemption"?
Never heard of it.
Focus, Danny!
Well, I gotta show you guys something now
if we're gonna do this.
Check it out.
Seriously?
I've been digging a hole into the wall.
It leads right into a sewage system.
This is our way out. It'll take us
right to the other side of the fence.
Wait. If you haven't seen
"The Carshank Redemption,"
where did you get the idea for this?
All right, get this.
I saw it in a movie once.
That movie was "Carshank Redemption"!
Nope. Never seen that one.
Oh, come on!
♪ They're all in jail ♪
Open cell 122!
Rita Carworth?
Oh my.
That is a huge hole.
Attention all Officers!
We have three cars on the loose.
They are not where they're supposed to be.
They are in big trouble.
Let's get outta here, man.
Why are we stopping?
We're here!
Where? Clunker Island?
No!
The Impossible Forest.
Dude! They must have
followed us from juvie.
They're gonna chase us until they get us!
So what do we do next?
We? What do you mean, "We"?
Typical. I knew you would bail on us.
I'm leaving.
Vin, you can't be serious!
100%. You have to save your dad.
Someone has to distract those cop cars.
You don't have to do this, Vin.
We can all escape together.
There's nothing for me on the outside,
but, Danny, you just make
sure you save your dad.
Wow. I guess I was wrong about him.
Honestly, I think we both were.
Well, we better book it.
Into the scary woods we go.
Let's get going.
- What?!
- Look!
Oh, no!
I feel like we've been
doing this for hours.
Are we going in circles?
Probably.
I swear I've seen this tree before.
How can you tell the
difference between trees?
I... I can't.
I can't!
Oh, no! I can't!
Pull yourself together, man!
Yes, pull yourselves together!
What was that?
It's just the forest playing tricks.
Yes, the forest playing tricks!
Okay, I heard that this tine.
I did, too.
Of course you did, dummies!
Do you think it's the spirit of the forest?
Yes, I am the spirit of the forest!
What are your three wishes?
Forest spirits grant wishes?
I don't know. Maybe.
What would you like?
Anything your heart desires!
Ooh, how 'bout we wish
our way to Clunker Island?
Or even better, we can wish for my dad!
Good thinking,
but we should probably start
out with something small.
Well, I am hungry.
How 'bout some food?
What kind?
Do you want to get Italian food?
Ethiopian food?
A nice salad?
Burritos?
Chimichangas?
Do you guys want to split a sub sandwich?
We have plenty of food.
Ooh, ooh! How 'bout a carburger?
We're all out of those.
Who are you?
I'm Kyle.
Are you the spirit of the forest?
Yes, I am.
Do you grant wishes?
No, I don't.
Hey, give that back!
Not until we get some answers.
What happened to our wishes?
I don't know. What happened to them?
Do you still grant them?
Uh, nope.
You aren't the spirit
of the forest, are you?
There isn't a spirit of the forest.
Then why did you lie to us?
Well, I have to pass the time somehow.
Do you know the way out of here?
Of course I do.
Well, can you tell us?
I can.
Well, are you gonna tell us?
Nope.
I thought you were gonna tell us.
No, I said I can.
I never said I would.
Well, now I know why
they call it the Impossible Forest.
Why?
'Cause he's impossible!
Well, that isn't very nice.
Come on, Danny.
We can figure this out without his help.
Wait!
What do you want?
I'll tell you how to leave,
but you have to do something for me.
What is it?
You scratch my back,
and I'll scratch yours.
Yeah, yeah, we get it.
What do you want?
No, that's literally what I want.
Scratch my back.
It itches.
I think there might be a
tree growing out of my back.
Fine.
You okay, Danny?
Uh, yeah.
It's just really moldy.
Gross!
Ah!
That's the spot!
Ooh! Ooh! Mmm.
Wait! Look.
Hmm,
what's so impossible about this forest?
Oh, don't pay attention
to any of the signs.
Why not?
Because they only work if you're lost,
and you're not lost.
Yes, we are.
No. You just don't know where you are.
That's lost!
No, lost is when you don't
know where you're going.
That makes some sort of sense.
So, Kyle, what do you suggest we do
to get out of the Impossible Forest?
Stay! Maybe plant a tree on your back.
We can have lengthy
conversations, sing songs,
complain and whine about our lives,
you know, fun stuff.
No, thanks.
We'll take our chances.
So long.
Bye! Sure you don't want
to sing a few songs before you go?
I can harmonize!
♪ La-la, la-la-la,
la-la, la-la ♪
♪ La-la, la-la,
la-la-la ♪
♪ In the forest ♪
Cabs, you have no idea how gross that was.
I can imagine.
I could smell it from a mile away.
Yeah, it was super...
Whoa!
Danny, we can't cross this bridge.
We have to.
This is the Dangerous Bridge.
Remember what Vin said?
The Incredibly Risky Port to Clunker Island
is on the other side.
These names don't sound reassuring.
Actually, now that I say them
out loud, they really don't.
There has to be another way across.
I don't see one.
Look, I'll go first.
Ooh!
Danny, come back!
You just watch me,
and go exactly where I go,
unless I fall.
You didn't have to say the last part.
Okay.
Whoa.
Okay, Cabbie! Easy does it!
That's one way.
Then there's this way.
Are you completely nuts?!
I just wanted to get it over with.
Anyway, maybe this bridge
isn't all that dangerous.
And then maybe it is.
Was.
Now it's on to the dock,
Port Incredibly Risky.
We want to go to Clunker Island.
You escaped from juvie?
Heh.
Yeah.
You got the pink slips?
Nope.
Okay, then.
You're good to go.
Come aboard.
Say, why do they call this
place Port Incredibly Risky?
They call it that?
- They do.
- News to me.
I guess it's because no one ever comes back
if they sail from this port,
at least, not in one piece.
I can see why it might
deserve that nickname.
Oh, and also the coin toss.
The what?
Heads or tails?
Uh, heads?
Heads, you get to go on the ferry.
Tails, I get to eat you.
- What?!
- Tails,
I get to cook you in WD-40 soup.
Danny, look at his teeth.
I didn't agree to that!
Too late.
I can't watch!
Come on, heads.
Come on, dinner.
I mean tails.
What is it?
It's heads!
Ah, thank goodness!
I guess I've got to wait
till the next ride to eat someone.
How do we know you won't
eat us during this ride?
Oh, I made up the whole coin toss thing
to live up to the name
Port Incredibly Risky.
I figured you'd believe it
'cause of my sharp teeth.
It's actually my first
day working at the port.
You can't be serious.
Anyway, enjoy the ride.
It may be the last one you ever take.
Please keep tires and
fenders inside the rails,
and no last-ditch suicide
leaps into the river.
No, no, no.
I don't like the looks of this.
I didn't expect anything this...
Bleak.
That works for me.
What do we do when we get there?
First, I deal with the locals.
They might be clunkers,
but, after all, we're all just cars.
Then I simply ask them where my dad is.
We grab him and take the ferry back.
Easy-peasy.
You really think it's gonna be easy-peasy?
No.
Maybe peasy.
Anybody here?
There must be somebody here.
Who wants to know?
So excited.
I'm Danny Carbunkle.
My dad is here somewhere,
and I'm here to get him and bring him home.
Are you, now?
How are you going to do that?
Any way I can. Who are you?
I'm the chief. I'm in charge here.
Do you know my dad?
His name is Art Carbunkle.
We don't know where your father is,
but you don't look totaled.
What are you doing on Clunker Island?
What are any of you
doing on Clunker Island?
We are here, because...
- ♪ We're clunkers ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
♪ We're just a bunch
of rundown junkers ♪
♪ We'll take your wheels ♪
♪ And use your hearts ♪
♪ And cannibalize your useful parts ♪
♪ Ooh hoo ♪
♪ Da da, da da, da da ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
♪ We're beyond all mending ♪
♪ Aaah ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
♪ This is where your story's ending ♪
♪ Chat ♪
♪ Ooh hoo ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
- ♪ Junkers ♪
♪ No one wants a rusty bumper ♪
♪ Pull your engine through your head ♪
♪ Lights go out before
you scream or shout ♪
♪ Ooh hoo ♪
♪ Na na na, na, na na na ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
- ♪ Junkers ♪
♪ Gears are cracked and failing ♪
♪ Aaah ♪
- ♪ Clunkers ♪
- ♪ Junkers ♪
♪ Just a bunch of salvaged slop ♪
♪ You could be the
next in the chop shop ♪
♪ Unless your crushed
and wheels go pop ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ Yah yah ♪
♪ Clunker cabaret ♪
♪ Junkyard jungle ♪
♪ Destruction derby ♪
♪ Pedal to the metal ♪
♪ Recycled remnants ♪
♪ Leftover chassis
that no one will claim ♪
♪ Hopeless heaters ♪
♪ Faulty meters ♪
♪ Blinking, beeping ♪
♪ Junkyard song ♪
♪ Compacted, battery acid, box of tin ♪
♪ Junkyard cabaret ♪
All right, all right! Enough!
What's her problem?
Yeah. You didn't have to be so mean.
Um, excuse me?
Huh? What?
You wanted to steal our parts and kill us!
When you put it that way,
it doesn't sound so nice.
It's better in a song.
Yeah, let's hit it, boys.
And a-one
and a-two...
No, no, no!
No more singing! Just stop.
We are trying to find my dad.
I do not know a car by the name of Dad.
What?
That bumper sticker,
it belonged to my dad. It's from his shop.
You don't think they stripped
him down for parts, do you?
I don't know what to think,
but my dad is here somewhere,
and I'm gonna find him.
What are we whispering about?
Scaredy-cars.
Where did you get that?
My bumper sticker? It's mine.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I don't believe you!
Tear them apart, piece by piece!
Uh-oh!
Can you please stop
getting us into trouble?
I'll work on that.
Leave her alone!
Stop, and cease, and desist!
What's the problem?
What are you doing?
Why are these strange new cars?
We were just going to tear them apart.
That's not okay.
These cars are my age.
I never meet anyone my age.
But, Carlotta...
If I don't like them,
you can tear them apart.
What is going on?
I'm not sure,
but I think we have to
make that one like us.
Who is she?
It's his daughter!
Daddy, call them off!
Yes, princess.
- Now!
- Stop!
Not again!
Oh, man.
See? I told you.
Always ruining our fun.
Yeah, that really concerned us.
Yep. So worried.
Let them go!
I need a new mirror.
Ugh. I need a new tire.
Thanks for saving us.
Yeah, thanks.
Quickly, follow me.
There isn't much space.
You mean time?
Time and space.
Good pun.
What pun?
Wait up!
Where are you going?
I know why your dad is.
You mean where my dad is?
Why? Where? Again with the puns?
What pun?
I will take you to the place why he is
if you do me one small favor.
Sure, anything.
There's no space now.
I'll tell you at a later space.
Where are we?
The Cave of Misery.
Why is it called that?
It's just a pun.
Okay, that's it.
Let's discuss the
definition of pun. It's...
Never mind, Cabigail.
Carlotta, where is it called that?
Ah, you're learning to speak
as a native of Clunker Island.
It's called the Cave of Misery, because...
Yes?
Because!
Nothing could be clearer to me now.
Your father, he's in there,
and now I must go before
my father catches me.
Wait!
She's long gone.
Yeah.
You think she's pretty.
No, I don't.
Sure!
You totally think she's pretty.
No, I don't! I think you're pretty!
You think I'm pretty?
No. I mean...
yes. I mean...
pretty cool.
Yeah, you're pretty cool.
Couldn't have done any of this without you.
Let's go in and save your dad.
Yeah.
Boy, is it dark in here.
What is that?
Sounds like a car.
A miserable car.
It's my dad!
She did say my dad was in here!
Only one way to find out.
Let there be light!
Hey, Cabs, can you turn
on your high beams also?
Way ahead of you.
Dad?
Dad, is that you?
Danny?
Dad!
It's so good to see you, Dad!
I'm gonna get you outta here!
I can't just leave.
I noticed.
You're missing a ton of parts.
- They took 'em.
- I knew it.
I thought I saw your
bumper sticker on the chief.
You shouldn't be here,
Danny. It's not safe.
Sometimes we have to do the right thing,
no matter the cost.
I got you into this mess.
I'm getting you out.
Please, Danny, j-just leave me here!
You need to get outta here right away!
Save yourself!
It's too late for me.
What are you doing?
Just seeing what parts are missing.
You need to leave here now!
Get away from Clunker Island
before your parts are cannibalized, too!
You can trust me, Dad.
He's gotten a lot more responsible.
Cabigail? You're here, too?
I should have guessed.
You never leave his side, do you?
Yeah. He's my best friend.
She reminds me of your mother.
You should date her.
Dad!
Just being honest. I...
I don't have too much time left.
They're gonna put me in a
trash compactor at sunup.
Every sunup, they sacrifice two cars.
I'm the second car.
Then we gotta go get your parts.
Get outta here! Just leave me!
Save yourself and Cabigail.
I came all this way.
I'm not giving up on you now!
I'm gonna be responsible and bold!
Wait! No!
It's too dangerous.
There's a Monster Truck!
Don't worry, Dad! I'll be back!
So what's the plan?
We're gonna steal back all my dad's parts.
I don't think the clunkers
are gonna like that.
Too bad for them.
Mess with a Carbunkle,
and you get what's coming to you.
My hero.
There!
That wreck's engine is purring.
Sounds just like my dad.
He must have his fuel pump.
Let's sneak inside and get it.
What are you doing?
We're gonna get my dad's parts back.
You can't do that!
And why not?
It is the law.
Anyone why breaks the law must do space.
- Huh?
- Must do time. Get it?
Oh, right.
Carlotta, you have to help us.
It's not right
to take a car apart and cannibalize it.
No. I want something for help.
What do you want?
Take me off this island.
I want to see the world.
I've never seen Monte Carlo.
Okay, but we live in Cargo, not Paris.
Very well, then! It's a deal!
To the glamorous town of Cargo!
Oh, you got lucky, laddie.
I'll get you next time.
Now we gotta get the bumper.
I won't stop you,
but for this part, I can't help.
I won't steal from my dad.
I understand completely.
Carlotta? Is that you?
Yes, Daddy.
Sorry to wake you.
Just go back to sleep.
I wasn't sleeping.
I was just idling
and thinking of all the
wonderful parts we'll take
from that idiot Carbunkle kid.
He's not an idiot.
What's that?
Nothing.
Nighty-night, Daddy.
Danny, what's wrong?
We weren't able to find
the most important part,
Dad's engine.
What are we gonna do?
You'll just have to get it,
but it won't be easy.
Thanks. We'll manage.
You're jealous.
Who? Me? Don't be ridiculous!
Carlotta, why are you helping us?
I want you to take me with you.
I want to see Cargo.
You've never seen Cargo?
Where are you from?
I'm from right here.
I've never been off Clunker Island.
But I thought this place was
just for cars that are totaled.
It is, except for me.
I was manufactured right here.
♪ I want to go where the autos are ♪
♪ Where everyone is a working car ♪
♪ Where people live by a moral code ♪
♪ And drive all day on the open road ♪
♪ I want to go where the autos are ♪
♪ A garage of my own ♪
♪ A paint job flaming red ♪
♪ A shiny new bumper ♪
♪ With headlights shining ♪
♪ Way ahead ♪
♪ I want to go where cars run free ♪
♪ Where I can be what I want to be ♪
♪ Where I can grow up
and do so much more ♪
♪ And one day, marry
the car next door ♪
♪ I want to go where cars are ♪
Danny, we have to take her!
Okay, Carlotta, you can come with us.
If you survive.
What do you mean?
Danny's father's truck engine
is now part of the Monster
Truck's collection of engines.
The Monster Truck?
Oh, no! Why is he here?
He already hates me for
beating him in the Demo Derby.
You totaled him at the Demolition Derby.
Oh, no. I'm the reason he's here.
He's gonna want revenge.
You want to get his engine,
you have to beat him again.
I'm faster than any old Monster Truck.
It's not a race.
Then what is it?
You have to butt heads with him,
mano y mano.
Well, I'm as much mano as he is.
But you're a lot more sensitive.
Well, I like some poetry and
appreciate the classics, but...
I meant sensitive to pain.
He'll be able to crush you.
Not if I have armor.
Where are you gonna get armor?
You could try the junkyard.
Some of my best friends live there.
This is where the cars that
haven't fully been repaired live.
Some have no engines.
Some have no wheels.
Some have no bumpers.
No bumpers? Don't they feel naked?
This is pitiful. Why are we here?
We're gonna borrow some armor.
I know a few old tanks that owe me a favor.
It's good to be the princess, you know.
Are you sure this is gonna work?
Yeah. This armor is unbreakable.
- What?
I said bring on the Monster Truck!
Hey, Monster Truck!
Who is that?
Danny Carbunkle.
What?
It's me, Danny Carbunkle.
I mean Chromio Shakescar, remember?
I'm the guy that put you here.
I remember!
You got a lot of guts facing me again!
I been dreaming about this moment!
I have, too, except it's a nightmare.
Those are pretty good-looking headlights.
Thanks. I like to keep 'em focused.
If I win, I get your engine.
Deal! It's on!
It's the Monster Truck
versus Danny Carbunkle!
You have two chances to win, kid,
slim and none,
and slim is out of gas!
Hurry, Danny!
You're running out of space!
At sunup, your dad will
be sent to the compactor!
Come on, Monster Truck!
Time to throw down!
♪ Sooner or later, I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Sooner or later,
you're gonna be mine ♪
♪ Sooner or later, I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Sooner or later,
you're gonna be mine ♪
♪ I'm gonna mush you ♪
♪ I'm gonna crush you ♪
♪ I'm gonna make you pay ♪
♪ I'm gonna smash you ♪
♪ I'm gonna thrash you ♪
♪ Go ahead, make my day ♪
♪ Sooner or later, I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Sooner or later,
you're gonna be mine ♪
♪ Sooner or later, I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ Sooner or later,
you're gonna be mine ♪
♪ I'm not afraid of you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're not cool ♪
♪ You're just an ugly beastmobile ♪
♪ And I'm nobody's fool ♪
♪ Diss me ♪
♪ You're gonna miss me ♪
♪ And spin your wheels ♪
♪ Ram me ♪
♪ Slam me ♪
♪ My armor is unreal ♪
♪ He's not afraid of you ♪
♪ He's just that cool ♪
♪ You're a fool like nobody ♪
♪ And he's nobody's fool ♪
♪ You can thump him ♪
♪ Bump him ♪
♪ He don't care ♪
♪ Stomp him ♪
♪ Whomp him ♪
Wait a minute! Don't give him any ideas!
Too late, kid!
I told you I would have my revenge!
Uh-oh!
You are mine, kid!
That was close.
Ah, you are a slippery
little heap, aren't you?
You missed me!
I'm just giving you false hope.
I won't miss again.
Danny, look out!
You're going down!
I'm gonna turn you into
a heap of twisted metal!
Danny, no!
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna take you out!
I'd like to see you try, little girl!
Uh-oh. I'm gonna get it again.
This is getting monotonous!
Danny!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
This armor's unbreakable, remember?
I was worried about you.
You don't need to worry about me.
I'm...
Danny.
Danny. Danny.
Sorry, Dad. Just five more minutes.
Danny, wake up.
What happened?
- You won.
- I did?
With a little help from your girlfriend.
I have a girlfriend?
She's not my girlfriend!
I am not his girlfriend.
Yeah. I mean, she's my
friend, and she's a girl,
but she's totally not my girlfriend.
And he is so not my boyfriend.
You guys are so cute.
Dad's engine!
You'd better get over there fast.
It's almost sunup.
What are waiting for?
Get me out of this stuff!
- Uh-oh.
- What?
Look.
As is the tradition every
morning on Clunker Island,
we must sacrifice two cars
to the Great Trash Compactor.
Forgive me, Father, for I had an oil leak.
You're going to a better place, my son.
May you rest in pieces.
Let's go!
Hurry!
The sun's about to come up!
Danny? Cabigail?
What are you doing here?
We're saving you!
It's too late, son.
No, it isn't! I'll be done in a jiffy.
You look factory fresh, Mr. Carbunkle.
Thanks to my boy here.
You'd do as much for me, Dad.
Well, you might still
need a little more work.
Be very, very quiet.
No one's supposed to leave Clunker Island.
Uh-oh.
Who's that?
It's just a dream.
Go back to sleep,
and dream of brand-new carburetors.
Carburetors.
Four for Cargo!
Huh?
Nobody ever leaves Clunker Island.
Then what are you waiting here for?
I can hope, can't I?
I am the princess of this island,
and I will go where I please,
and I'll take anyone with me.
Yes, Princess, as you wish,
but you may not take any clunkers with you.
As you can see, none of us are clunkers.
Hmm. You dummies
were the ones who won
the coin toss earlier.
Care to try your luck again? Hmm?
Just let us on the ferry!
Fine! You guys don't
look like clunkers anyway.
What a crazy first week.
Wait'll the other ferry
guys hear about this.
Stop them! Nobody leaves Clunker Island!
Come on, guys.
Bye, Daddy! I'll write!
But you don't know how to write.
So, tell me more about Cargo.
Well, we have drive-in movies,
carwashes, and lots of boys.
Not ones that have been put
together from broken cars?
No, shiny showroom
models with new-car smell,
low mileage, and totally smooth engines.
Will I fit in?
Are you kidding?
All you need is a good car wash,
and you'll be the prettiest car in town.
Thanks for saying that, even if it's a fib.
I wish it was a fib.
I saw how Danny looks at you.
You're blind, aren't you?
What do you mean? You are gorgeous.
Anyone could see that.
I wouldn't be so sure he's looking at me.
He only has eyes for you.
What, me? Never!
Danny and I are just friends.
He wouldn't...
Talk, talk, talk. Pay attention, girl.
I'm very proud of you, son.
Thanks, Dad, but I need to do something.
What?
- Hey, Cabs?
- Yes?
Now that this is all over,
do you want to maybe...
I don't know...
hang out sometime?
We hang out all the time.
I told you so.
No, I mean, like,
because you saved me and all,
maybe I can take you
to dinner or something.
Quit being so weird.
It's a date.
A date? Really?
I mean, sure, whatever.
It's cool and everything.
Oh, no! Dad, it's Fred Copcar!
We're gonna get sent back!
Fred and I go way back.
Let me talk to him.
Everything is gonna be fine.
You and Fred Copcar go way back?
Okay, guys, we will have our
new pink slips in the morning.
Fred will see to that.
He what? How do you even know him?
We used to race together.
You used to race?!
- Yep.
- Wow!
Then why did you tell me not to?
I just didn't want to see you
make the same mistakes I made.
Your dad is a great guy.
I just want to help you kids.
I'm just in shock right now, really.
Many years ago, he saved my life.
Yeah?
Then why did you send us to juvie?
You said you had to get to Clunker Island
to save your dad, didn't you?
Well, you guys were able to
sneak over there from the juvie.
I knew your friend Vin had been going
all "Carshank Redemption"
over there, tunneling out.
Finally, someone has seen that movie!
Thanks for everything, Fred.
You really saved my bumper. I owe you one.
Actually, I think I still owe you one.
I know things have been
slow at the mechanic shop.
I got something that just opened up.
Really?
Really.
I need a new fleet of cars
fixed up for the station.
It's gonna be a lot of work.
Sounds like more than a one-man job.
I could only do it if I had some help
from someone really good
at putting cars together.
Where would I find a car like that?
Maybe one that was able to
put me back together again?
Me?
Yeah, you.
Are you sure, Dad?
I mean, I'm honored,
but do you think I can?
I know you can, Danny.
I mean, you are amazing at it,
but you don't seem to like doing it.
I think I only didn't like it,
because you were doing it.
But you're right. It's
something I'm good at.
Like you said, it's in my oil.
It's in our oil!
♪ Welcome to Cargo, my hometown ♪
♪ So many great cars here ♪
♪ Old and new, from green and brown ♪
♪ The residents are pretty swell ♪
♪ And I can tell, I know them well ♪
♪ The children here are well-behaved ♪
♪ But my son is an adult ♪
♪ My life he saved ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, it's
one heck of a town ♪
♪ With some streets going up ♪
♪ And others going down ♪
♪ Cargo, Cargo, to
us, it's very clear ♪
♪ If this is where you lived ♪
♪ You'd be home by now ♪
♪ So move your family here ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull